Guide to the Jean Giono Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Jean Giono collection
1938-1970
GEN MSS 458
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.29
(2 boxes)
One letter from Giono to Blanche Meyer, undated; one letter to "Cher Brun", 1935 Nov 30; three undated letters from Giono to an unidentified recipient; holograph and typescript notes for and drafts of "Que ma joie demeure".
Giono, Jean, 1895-1970
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded on the folders. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Blanche Meyer Collection of Jean Giono, GEN MSS 457
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Jean Giono, acquired by the library from a variety of sources. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to January 2000 have been organized into 2 series: I. Letters, and II. Writings. Materials acquired since that date are listed in Series III. Additions Since January 2000.
Que ma joie demeure; Giono, Jean, 1895-1970; Meyer, Blanche, 1908-1988
- Letters, 1935 Nov 30; Series I
  - Letter: to "Cher Brun", 1935 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Acc. #: 19900718-l
  - Letter: to Blanche Meyer, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Acc. #:19900718-k
  - Letter: to Unidentified, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Lus la Croix Haute
  - Letter: to Unidentified, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Manosque
  - Letter: to Unidentified, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Writings, n.d.; Series II
  - "Que ma joie demeure": notes and draft pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes note explaining contents
  - "Que ma joie demeure": printed version with added manuscript notes, ca. 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Privately printed edition [n.p.; Editions Grasset; "Pour Mon Plaisir II", 1935 - Number 5 of 6 on "Chine" paper] Tipped-in items: Holograph notes comprising the beginning pages of the book - sent to Jean Simon along with an accompanying letter.
    Manuscript items in fragile condition: Use copies provided in accompanying folder 8
  - Photocopies of Manuscript items in "Que ma joie demeure", ca. 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additions Since January 2000, n.d.; Series III
  - Letter to Blanche Meyer, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Acc.: 20010424-c